As a little girl, I always imagined
عندما كنت طفلة، تخيلت دائمًا
I would one day run away.
أنني سأهرب بعيدًا يومًا ما.
From the age of six on,
من عمر السادسة،
I kept a packed bag with some clothes
بدأت الاحتفاظ ببعض الملابس في كيس
and cans of food tucked away
وخبأت بعض علب الطعام
in the back of a closet.
خلف الخزانة.
There was a deep restlessness in me,
كان هنالك شعور داخلي عميق بعدم الاستقرار،
a primal fear that I would fall prey
خوفٌ بدائي أنني سأقع ضحية
to a life of routine and boredom.
لروتين الحياة والملل.
And so, many of my early memories involved
أغلب ذكرياتي المبكرة شملت
intricate daydreams where I would walk across borders,
أحلام يقظة أمشي فيها وأعبر الحدود،
forage for berries,
متناسيةً الحواجز،
and meet all kinds of strange people
أقابل أناس غرباء من كل الأنواع
living unconventional lives on the road.
يعيشون حياة غير تقليدية على الطريق.
Years have passed, but many of the adventures
مرت الأعوام، لكن أغلب المغامرات
I fantasized about as a child --
التي تخيلتها وأنا طفلة،
traveling and weaving my way
أسافر وأشق طريقي
between worlds other than my own —
بين عوالم غير عالمي الخاص،
have become realities through my work
أصبحت واقعا من خلال عملي
as a documentary photographer.
كمصورة وثائقية.
But no other experience has felt as true
لكن ولا تجربة أحسست أنها حقيقة
to my childhood dreams
مثل أحلام طفولتي
as living amongst and documenting the lives
غير تجربة العيش وتوثيق حياة
of fellow wanderers across the United States.
زملاء متشردين عبر الولايات المتحدة.
This is the nomadic dream,
هذا هو الحلم المترحل،
a different kind of American dream
نوع آخر من الحلم الأمريكي
lived by young hobos, travelers,
يعيشه شباب متجولون ومسافرون،
hitchhikers, vagrants and tramps.
ومتنقلون ومتشردون وصعاليك.
In most of our minds,
في أغلب عقولونا،
the vagabond is a creature from the past.
المتشرد مخلوق أصبح من الماضي.
The word "hobo" conjures up an old
كلمة "متشرد" تستحضر
black and white image
صورة قديمة بالأبيض والأسود
of a weathered old man covered in coal,
لرجل شاحب اللون مغطى بالفحم،
legs dangling out of a boxcar,
أقدام تتدلى خارج عربة السيارة،
but these photographs are in color,
لكن هذه الصور ملونة،
and they portray a community
وتصف مجتمعًا
swirling across the country,
يدور حول البلاد،
fiercely alive and creatively free,
حيٌ بشدة وحرٌ بإبداع،
seeing sides of America that no one else
يرون جوانب من أمريكا لم يحظ أحد
gets to see.
برؤيتها.
Like their predecessors, today's nomads
كما كان أسلافهم، مشرديّ اليوم
travel the steel and asphalt arteries
يرتحلون على الشرايين الحديدية والأسفلتية
of the United States.
للولايات المتحدة.
By day, they hop freight trains, stick out their thumbs,
في النهار، يقفزون على القطارات، يؤشرون بإبهامهم،
and ride the highways with anyone
ويركبون الطرقات السريعة مع أي كان
from truckers to soccer moms.
من قائدي الشاحانات إلى أمهات الضواحي.
By night, they sleep beneath the stars,
في الليل، ينامون تحت النجوم،
huddled together with their packs of dogs,
يجتمعون مع بعضهم ويحشدون كلابهم،
cats and pet rats between their bodies.
قططهم، وفئرانهم بين أجسادهم.
Some travelers take to the road by choice,
بعض المسافرين يختارون الطريق بمحض إرادتهم،
renouncing materialism, traditional jobs
نابذين الحياة المادية، والوظائف التقليدية
and university degrees in exchange for a glimmer of adventure.
والدرجات الجامعية مقابل بريق المغامرة.
Others come from the underbelly of society,
آخرون قدموا من أسفل المجتمع،
never given a chance to mobilize upwards:
لم يعطوا أبدًا فرصة للصعود إلى أعلى:
foster care dropouts, teenage runaways escaping
متسربين من الحضانات، مراهقين هاربين
abuse and unforgiving homes.
من إيذاء المنازل التي لا ترحم.
Where others see stories of privation
بينما يراهم البعض قصصا للحرمان
and economic failure,
والفشل الاقتصادي،
travelers view their own existence
يرى الرحّالة وجودهم
through the prism of liberation and freedom.
من منظور العتق والحرية.
They'd rather live off of the excess
يفضلون العيش من فائض
of what they view as a wasteful consumer society
ما يرون أنه مجتمع استهلاكي مسرف
than slave away at an unrealistic chance
على العيش في استعباد من أجل فرصة غير واقعية
at the traditional American dream.
في الحلم الأمريكي التقليدي.
They take advantage of the fact
لقد استغلوا حقيقة
that in the United States,
أنه في الولايات المتحدة
up to 40 percent of all food ends up in the garbage
حوالي 40 % من الطعام يذهب للنفايات
by scavenging for perfectly good produce
بالبحث عن المنتجات الجيدة كليًا
in dumpsters and trash cans.
في الحاويات وعلب القمامة.
They sacrifice material comforts in exchange
لقد ضحوا بالراحة المادية مقابل
for the space and the time to explore
المساحة والزمن لاكتشاف
a creative interior,
الإبداع الداخلي،
to dream, to read, to work on music, art and writing.
للحلم، للقراءة، لتأليف الموسيقى، للفن وللكتابة.
But there are many aspects to this life
لكن هناك جوانب آخرى لهذه الحياة
that are far from idyllic.
بعيدة كليًا عن المثالية.
No one loses their inner demons
لا أحد يفقد شياطينه الداخلية
by taking to the road.
بالعيش على الطرقات.
Addiction is real, the elements are real,
الإدمان حقيقي، والمخدرات حقيقية،
freight trains maim and kill,
تشويه قاطرات الشحن والقتل،
and anyone who has lived on the streets can attest
أي أحد عاش في الشوارع يستطيع إثبات
to the exhaustive list of laws
قائمة القوانين المفصلة
that criminalize homeless existence.
التي تجرّم وجود المشردين.
Who here knows that in many cities
من منكم يعلم أنه في عدة مدن
across the United States it is now illegal
عبر الولايات المتحدة أصبح الآن غير قانوني
to sit on the sidewalk,
أن تجلس على قارعة الطريق،
to wrap oneself in a blanket,
أن تغطي نفسك بلحاف،
to sleep in your own car,
أن تنام في سيارتك الخاصة،
to offer food to a stranger?
أو أن تقدم طعامًا لشخص غريب؟
I know about these laws because I've watched
أنا أعلم عن تلك القوانين لأنني رأيت
as friends and other travelers
أصدقاء ورحّالة آخرين
were hauled off to jail or received citations
سحبوا إلى السجن أو تلقوا دعوات
for committing these so-called crimes.
بارتكاب ما سمّي بجرائم.
Many of you might be wondering why anyone
أغلبكم قد يتسائل لما أي شخص
would choose a life like this,
قد يختار حياة كهذه،
under the thumb of discriminatory laws,
بالبقاء تحت ضغط قوانين التمييز،
eating out of trash cans,
الأكل من علب النفايات،
sleeping under bridges,
النوم تحت الجسور،
picking up seasonal jobs here and there.
الحصول على أعمال موسمية هنا وهناك.
The answer to such a question is as varied
والجواب على سؤال كهذا متنوع
as the people that take to the road,
بتنوع الأشخاص على الطرقات،
but travelers often respond with a single word:
لكن الرحّالة غالبًا ما يجيبون بكلمة واحدة:
freedom.
الحرية.
Until we live in a society where every human
إلى حين أن نعيش في مجتمع يكون كل إنسان
is assured dignity in their labor
قد ضمن الكرامة في عمله
so that they can work to live well,
بحيث يعملون لأجل العيش الكريم،
not only work to survive,
وليس فقط للبقاء على قيد الحياة،
there will always be an element of those
فسيبقى هناك دائمًا دافع لهؤلاء
who seek the open road as a means of escape,
الذين يبحثون عن الطرق المفتوحة كوسيلة للهرب
of liberation and, of course, of rebellion.
للعتق، وبالطبع للتمرد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)